FAJAR SUJITO

Cilacap • 081903492372 • fjarfs@gmail.com

fajarsujito.net



Web & Mobile Developer

Summary

I spend about 4 years 1 month 11 days to study at Semarang State University, more precisely in the Department of Computer Science. I am hardworking, confident and like a new things. So during my lecture I had been a Student Staff, Laboratory Assistant, Lecturer Assistant, and even once attended Student Exchange to Hiroshima University, Japan. In my job matters very professional, thorough and responsible. Besides it can work both in teams and individuals. This is proven by trusted some people or companies in the development of websites and Android applications. My portfolio can be viewed at https://fajarsujito.net.

Work experience

2018 - Present

Lead Backend Developer

DXTR, Jakarta - Indonesia

System analysis, database structure and application development with microservices architecture, structure optimization, and failure. Collaborate with business teams, project managers, technical leaders, and CTOs to achieve mutually beneficial goals on all projects. As a Lead Backend, reviewing code / work from the backend team, working together with the Frontend team and Quality Assurance to ensure the application developed has no bugs or minimize bugs. Become a technical decision maker in backend the system and ensure good application performance. Several applications have been built such as Spotme, Toyota Admin (Toyota), AYO-SRC (Sampoerna), and IQOS (Sampoerna). Technologies used in system development include: PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Amazon RDS, Firebase, Nginx, React Js, React Native, Html, CSS, Angular Js, GIT, Jira, Amazon EC2, Amazon ECS, Docker, Jenkins, DynamoDB, Redis, Newrelic, SonarQube

Accomplishments:

• Build applications in the Microservices architecture

2018 - 2018

Full Stack Developer

PT Internet Solusi Layanan Informasi Mandiri, Depok - Indonesia

The main task is developing GIS applications. Coordinate with CTO and business team regarding the criteria of the system to be built. Analyzing database structure and user interfaces. Applications that are built are company profile, E-commerce, E-Government, GIS, and application administrators and reports. technology used in developing applications is PHP, CI, PostgreSQL, Apache, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax, Html, CSS, Trello

2016 - 2017

Chief Programmer

Starcomtechnology, Semarang - Indonesia

As the leader of the programmer, in charge of designing the system structure, database structure, and analyzing the developed system. In addition, it also develops programs, tests, and manages the programmer team. Working closely with business teams, project manager and CEO. Applications that are built are employment management applications, learning document management

systems, cooperative accounting systems, cashier management systems, warehouses and reporting, and E-commerce. In development all applications consist of several technologies such as: PHP, Laravel, CI, MySQL, Html, CSS, Ajax, Javascript, jQuery, MVC, GIT, trello.

Technical Summary

Backend

- PHP
- Laravel
- Codeigniter
- MySQL
- DynamoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Redis
- Microservices
- ElasticSearch
- Amazon RDS

Frontend

- Javascript
- React Js
- React Native
- Angular Js
- CSS
- HTML
- jQuery
- Delphi

Other

- Docker
- Apache
- Nginx
- GIT
- Firebase
- Jenkins
- Cloudflare
- Amazon EC2
- Amazon ECS

Education

2013 - 2017 Bachelor of Computer Science

Semarang State University

Indonesia

2016 - 2016 International Development and Cooperation (IDEC)

Hiroshima University

Hiroshima, Japan

(Short course)

2010 - 2013 Senior High School

SMA Negeri 1 Majenang

Indonesia